77 Benevolent Elephants.
77 仁慈的大象。
I can hardly do this one.
我几乎做不到这个。
Why practice tongue twisters?
为什么要练习绕口令？
My students who have problems with some of the sounds of American English need to train their mind to guide their mouth to effortlessly go through the positions for these sounds.
我的学生中有些人对美式英语的某些发音有困难，他们需要训练自己的大脑来引导嘴巴轻松地完成这些发音的位置。
Tongue twisters can help with this.
绕口令可以帮助实现这一点。
They can help build the brain connection.
它们可以帮助建立大脑连接。
This is a TH.
这是一个TH音。
So that your body can do it on its own without thinking of it, without the mind having to guide the tongue through the position.
这样你的身体就可以在不思考的情况下自动完成，而不需要大脑引导舌头通过位置。
And that's what we want.
这就是我们想要的。
Of course, we want the habit.
当然，我们想要习惯。
We want to take the sounds that are hardest and make them effortless.
我们想要把最难的发音变得毫不费力。
So today we're going to go over some tongue twisters to untwist your tongue and help you master some of the trickiest consonant sounds of American English.
所以今天我们要练习一些绕口令来解开你的舌头，帮助你掌握美式英语中一些最棘手的辅音发音。
As always, if you like this video or you learn something new, please give it a thumbs up and subscribe with notifications and come join us on Tuesdays for new videos.
一如既往，如果你喜欢这个视频或学到了新东西，请点赞并订阅通知，并在周二加入我们观看新视频。
Today we're training three super tricky tongue twisters.
今天我们要训练三个超级棘手的绕口令。
First, 77 Benevolent Elephants.
首先，77 仁慈的大象。
This is going to help with your V.
这将帮助你练习V音。
My students from India and Germany tend to sometimes switch V and W.
我的印度和德国学生有时会把V和W混淆。
And these can be tricky sounds for other language groups as well.
这些对其他语言群体来说也可能是棘手的发音。
Mastering this tongue twister will help your brain really get that V is V.
掌握这个绕口令将帮助你的大脑真正理解V就是V。
We're also going to do which wristwatches are Swiss wristwatches.
我们还要练习“哪只手表是瑞士手表”。
Hitting the W hard, also the R.
重读W音，也重读R音。
That's because the W is silent in the word wristwatch.
因为在“wristwatch”这个词中，W是无声的。
Wrist.
Wrist。
Look out.
小心。
This one is really tricky.
这个真的很棘手。
And I'm not going to forget that ever important T.H.
我不会忘记那个非常重要的T.H.音。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
You'll get to work on your R in that one, too.
你也可以在这个练习中练习你的R音。
What other tongue twisters do you know?
你还知道哪些绕口令？
Put them in the comments below.
请在下面的评论中写出来。
Let's look at our first one.
让我们看看第一个。
77 Benevolent Elephants.
77 仁慈的大象。
That's a lot of elephants.
那是很多大象。
Benevolent means kind, expressing goodwill, helping others.
仁慈的意思是善良，表达善意，帮助他人。
You usually don't think of an elephant as being benevolent, but it does make a good tongue twister.
你通常不会认为大象是仁慈的，但它确实是一个很好的绕口令。
This one is tricky, too fast, and even native speakers mess it up.
这个也很棘手，太快了，甚至母语者也会搞错。
This is my friend Ginny and her daughter Natalie.
这是我的朋友Ginny和她的女儿Natalie。
77 Benevolent Elephant.
77 仁慈的大象。
I don't know.
我不知道。
77 Benevolent Elephants.
77 仁慈的大象。
And this is my sister-in-law Audrey.
这是我的嫂子Audrey。
77 Benevolent Elephants.
77 仁慈的大象。
We'll focus on the word benevolent.
我们将专注于“benevolent”这个词。
First, it helps so much with longer words to focus on stress.
首先，专注于重音对较长的单词帮助很大。
The second syllable here is stressed.
这里的第二个音节是重音。
Let's practice just that.
让我们只练习这个。
Nev.
Nev。
It's like a hill.
就像一个小山。
Nev.
Nev。
It has our tricky V sound.
它有我们棘手的V音。
V, not W, no lip rounding.
V，不是W，没有唇部圆形。
Nev.
Nev。
Next, unstressed.
接下来，不重读。
The first syllable is just buh.
第一个音节只是buh。
Buh.
Buh。
Very simple, very fast.
非常简单，非常快。
Let's put it with the stressed syllable.
让我们把它和重读音节放在一起。
Benev.
Benev。
Remember, these two syllables should feel totally different.
记住，这两个音节应该感觉完全不同。
One is stressed, one is unstressed.
一个是重读，一个是不重读。
The first one, very fast.
第一个，非常快。
The second one is longer.
第二个更长。
It has that hill shape.
它有那个小山形状。
Benev.
Benev。
Our other two syllables, all in.
我们的其他两个音节，all in。
All three of these unstressed syllables here have the schwa pronounced like this.
这里的所有三个不重读音节都有schwa音，发音像这样。
Buh.
Buh。
Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
Almost no jaw drop, totally relaxed face.
几乎没有下巴下垂，完全放松的脸。
It almost looks like I'm not even talking.
看起来我几乎没有在说话。
Buh.
Buh。
Buh-lint.
Buh-lint。
Benev-lint.
Benev-lint。
Benevolent.
Benevolent。
Put them together, but don't slow down those fast syllables.
把它们放在一起，但不要放慢那些快速音节。
Keep them fast.
保持快速。
Keep it simple.
保持简单。
Benevolent.
Benevolent。
benevolent.
benevolent。
Seventy-seven benevolent elephants.
七十七只仁慈的大象。
The next word, elephants, that first syllable has the hill shape, the stress.
下一个词，大象，第一个音节有小山形状，重读。
Practice it with me.
和我一起练习。
El, el.
El, el。
The other two syllables, schwas, said more quickly.
其他两个音节，schwa音，更快地说。
Elephant, elephant, elephant.
Elephant, elephant, elephant。
Put it together.
把它放在一起。
Elephant.
Elephant。
The PH makes an F sound.
PH发F音。
Did you know F and V have the same mouth position?
你知道F和V有相同的口型吗？
F is unvoiced, meaning just air makes the sound.
F是无声的，意味着只有空气发出声音。
And V is voiced, meaning your vocal cords are engaged, making a sound.
而V是有声的，意味着你的声带参与发声。
All alternate.
交替发音。
See that nothing in the mouth changes.
看看嘴里什么都没有改变。
Let's put the two words together.
让我们把这两个词放在一起。
It's gonna be common to make the ending T a stop T.
通常会把结尾的T做成停顿T。
Stop the air in your throat, but don't release T, the T sound.
在喉咙里停止空气，但不要释放T音。
Benevolent.
Benevolent。
Benevolent elephants.
Benevolent elephants。
Okay, move your arm on those stressed syllables.
好吧，在重读音节上移动你的手臂。
Benevolent elephants.
Benevolent elephants。
Do it as slowly as you need to to make sure you're doing it correctly.
慢慢地做，确保你做得正确。
Remember, we wanna train the right positions.
记住，我们想要训练正确的位置。
Seventy-seven.
七十七。
This is gonna help us train that V sound some more.
这将帮助我们更多地训练V音。
Both parts of the words have first syllable stress.
这两个词的第一音节都有重读。
Seventy, seven.
Seventy, seven。
Seventy-seven.
Seventy-seven。
Notice I'm making that T more of a D or a flap T sound.
注意我把T发成D或轻拍T音。
This is an exception.
这是个例外。
Usually, after an N, it's either dropped or a true T.
通常，在N之后，要么省略，要么是真T音。
But here it's a flap T.
但这里是轻拍T音。
Seventy.
Seventy。
Seventy-seven.
Seventy-seven。
Okay, I'm gonna try it now.
好吧，我现在要试试。
Seventy-seven benevolent elephants.
七十七只仁慈的大象。
If a V sound is at all tricky for you, do this over and over slowly.
如果V音对你来说有点棘手，慢慢地多做几遍。
Get it down good.
把它练好。
This will help.
这会有帮助。
Don't go so fast that you're doing it incorrectly.
不要太快，以至于做错。
You wanna practice doing it right.
你要练习正确地做。
Then you can speed it up.
然后你可以加快速度。
Our second tongue twister today is which wristwatches are Swiss wristwatches?
我们今天的第二个绕口令是“哪只手表是瑞士手表？”
This one is so hard.
这个太难了。
Which wristwatches are Swiss wristwatches?
哪只手表是瑞士手表？
I can't do it quickly at all.
我根本不能快速地做。
Look at all these W and R sounds.
看看这些W和R音。
W, R in red.
W，R用红色。
R in blue.
R用蓝色。
Beginning R and W actually look a lot alike from the outside.
开头的R和W从外面看起来很像。
Watch.
Watch。
Rrrrrrr.
Rrrrrrr。
Lots of lip rounding.
很多唇部圆形。
But what's happening inside is pretty different.
但内部发生的事情非常不同。
For the R, the middle part of the tongue lifts towards the roof of the mouth.
对于R，舌头的中部抬向上颚。
The tip is backing up, not touching anything.
舌尖向后缩，不接触任何东西。
For the W, the tongue tip touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
对于W，舌尖接触下前牙的后面。
Then the back stretches up.
然后后部向上伸展。
And we have a little something extra in the throat.
我们在喉咙里有一点额外的东西。
W, w, just a little narrowing here.
W, w, 只是这里有一点收缩。
W, w, rrrrrrrr.
W, w, rrrrrrrr。
Wrist.
Wrist。
Watch.
Watch。
If R is at all a problem for you or W, then nailing this tongue twister, slowing it down, getting it right is gonna help you out.
如果R或W对你来说有问题，那么掌握这个绕口令，慢慢地做，做对会对你有帮助。
Let's do just the first two words.
让我们只做前两个词。
Which wrist.
Which wrist。
Both have the I as in sit vowel.
都有I音，像在sit中的元音。
Which wrist.
Which wrist。
And both have that hill shape.
都有小山形状。
They're both stressed.
它们都是重读的。
Which wrist.
Which wrist。
Do that with me slowly.
慢慢地和我一起做。
Which wrist.
Which wrist。
Wrist.
Wrist。
Which wrist.
Which wrist。
Let's put in the second half of our compound word, watches.
让我们加入复合词的后半部分，watches。
In a compound word, the first word is stressed, so watches is unstressed.
在复合词中，第一个词是重读的，所以watches是不重读的。
Watches.
Watches。
It doesn't have that hill shape.
它没有小山形状。
It's flatter.
它更平。
Wristwatches.
Wristwatches。
Say that with me.
和我一起说。
Wristwatches.
Wristwatches。
Which wristwatches.
Which wristwatches。
Okay, this reminds me of another terribly hard tongue twister.
好吧，这让我想起另一个非常难的绕口令。
I wish to wash my Irish wristwatch.
我想洗我的爱尔兰手表。
I made my nieces and my nieces fiance try that one out a couple of years ago.
几年前我让我的侄女和她的未婚夫试过这个。
It was not pretty.
结果不太好。
I wish to wash my Irish wristwatch.
我想洗我的爱尔兰手表。
This one, I think, is slightly easier.
这个，我觉得稍微简单一点。
Next word is R.
下一个词是R。
This word won't be stressed.
这个词不会重读。
In fact, in lots of sentences, a native speaker would just say R.
事实上，在很多句子中，母语者只会说R。
Where are the kids?
孩子们在哪里？
Where?
在哪里？
R, R, R, R.
R，R，R，R。
For example, let's try that.
例如，让我们试试这个。
Just R on the end of watches.
只是在手表的末尾加上R。
Which wristwatches are?
哪些手表是？
Watches are, watches are, watches are.
手表是，手表是，手表是。
Reducing R.
减少R。
Next, Swiss.
接下来，瑞士。
We have another W lip rounding.
我们有另一个W唇形。
Swiss, Swiss.
瑞士，瑞士。
This is also stressed with that hill shape a little bit longer.
这也强调了那个小山形状，稍微长一点。
Swiss.
瑞士。
Which wristwatches are Swiss?
哪些手表是瑞士的？
Do it slowly and accurately.
慢慢地、准确地做。
Which wristwatches are Swiss?
哪些手表是瑞士的？
Notice, even when I'm going slowly, I'm connecting all the words in the line.
注意，即使我慢慢地说，我也在连接这行中的所有单词。
We want that.
我们想要那样。
No breaks, no separation, all smoothly linked.
没有中断，没有分离，全部顺畅地连接。
That's something we just love in English.
这是我们在英语中非常喜欢的东西。
Which wristwatches are Swiss?
哪些手表是瑞士的？
Now, all we need is wristwatches again.
现在，我们只需要再说一次手表。
Which wristwatches are Swiss wristwatches?
哪些手表是瑞士手表？
Have you got that?
你明白了吗？
Take your time.
慢慢来。
Do it daily.
每天练习。
The final tongue twister that we're practicing today is pretty tough.
我们今天练习的最后一个绕口令相当难。
My sister-in-law and niece could not get it.
我的嫂子和侄女都做不到。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
He threw...
他投了...
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
Natalie couldn't get it either.
娜塔莉也做不到。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
Not quite.
不太对。
Julia, nope.
朱莉娅，不行。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
Let's give Ginny a try.
让我们给金妮试试。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个罚球。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
She says no.
她说不行。
She can't do it.
她做不到。
But you can do it.
但你可以做到。
We can do it if we slow it down, get it good, and then speed it up.
如果我们慢下来，做好，然后加快速度，我们就能做到。
And if you master this, your TH is going to be a lot clearer and THR will be way less intimidating.
如果你掌握了这个，你的TH会更清晰，THR会不那么令人生畏。
This one is extra tough because we're dealing not just with TH and F, but with clusters, with R.
这个特别难，因为我们不仅要处理TH和F，还要处理R的组合。
Three.
三。
Free.
免费。
A lot of little kids can't even say TH, actually.
很多小孩子甚至不能说TH。
They say F instead.
他们说F代替。
I remember when my son Stoney did that.
我记得我儿子斯托尼那样做过。
Marf.
马夫。
So you're going marf.
所以你在说马夫。
You're using your lip, but we want to use your tongue.
你在用你的嘴唇，但我们想用你的舌头。
No, almost.
不，差不多。
Bring your tongue.
把你的舌头带过来。
He wasn't very interested in learning that day, was he?
那天他对学习不太感兴趣，是吗？
To make the unvoiced TH like through, three, and throws, your tongue tip has to come through the teeth.
要发无声的TH音，比如through，three和throws，你的舌尖必须穿过牙齿。
Th, th, th.
Th，th，th。
Just air.
只有空气。
No tension.
没有紧张。
No holding.
没有停顿。
No stopping.
没有停止。
Th, th, th.
Th，th，th。
Easy sound.
简单的声音。
Let's alternate between three and free.
让我们在three和free之间交替。
I'll zoom in.
我会放大。
Three.
三。
Free.
免费。
Three.
三。
Free.
免费。
Three.
三。
Free.
免费。
You can do it.
你可以做到。
It takes practice, but you can get it.
这需要练习，但你可以做到。
He threw.
他投了。
Let's just do that.
我们就做这个。
Threw is stressed.
投是重音。
He threw.
他投了。
Three is also stressed, another THR cluster.
三也是重音，另一个THR组合。
So for the THR, you go for the tongue tip being just out.
所以对于THR，你要让舌尖稍微伸出。
Th, to being pulled back and up a little bit.
Th，稍微往后拉一点。
Thrr.
Thrr。
Slow it down.
慢下来。
Feel that movement in the tip of your tongue.
感受舌尖的运动。
Thrr.
Thrr。
He threw three.
他投了三个。
Free is also stressed.
免费也是重音。
Here, you do want to use your bottom lip.
在这里，你确实要用下唇。
Th, th, th.
Th，th，th。
Free.
免费。
And then throws, unstressed.
然后是投，非重音。
Free throws.
免费投。
Th, th, th.
Th，th，th。
Free throws.
免费投。
Do that with me slowly.
和我一起慢慢做。
Th, th, th.
Th，th，th。
Free throws.
免费投。
You can hold out the consonant.
你可以拖长辅音。
Right mouth position.
正确的口腔位置。
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个免费投。
Practicing slowly gives your mind time to guide your tongue into the right position.
慢慢练习给你的大脑时间引导你的舌头到正确的位置。
And once your brain does that enough, you won't have to think about it anymore.
一旦你的大脑这样做够多次，你就不需要再想了。
The habit will be made.
习惯就会形成。
Our three tongue twisters today are all training problem consonant sounds in English for non-native speakers.
我们今天的三个绕口令都是为非母语者训练英语中的问题辅音。
Take your time.
慢慢来。
Get it right.
做对。
Form that pathway in the brain.
在大脑中形成那条路径。
Let's do it.
让我们开始吧。
Seventy-seven benevolent elephants.
七十七头仁慈的大象。
Which wristwatches are Swiss wristwatches?
哪些手表是瑞士手表？
He threw three free throws.
他投了三个免费投。
And as you get more comfortable, you can increase your speed.
当你越来越熟练时，你可以加快速度。
Tongue twisters are actually kind of fun, aren't they?
绕口令其实挺有趣的，不是吗？
Huge thanks to my friends and family for helping me out with this video.
非常感谢我的朋友和家人帮助我制作这个视频。
They're not afraid of a few tongue twisters.
他们不怕几个绕口令。
Audrey, Emily, Molly, Taylor, Ginny, Natalie, and Julia, thank you.
奥黛丽，艾米莉，莫莉，泰勒，金妮，娜塔莉和朱莉娅，谢谢你们。
I hope you learned and going now with this video.
我希望你学到了东西，现在就去看这个视频。
And don't forget to subscribe.
别忘了订阅。
I make new videos every Tuesday, and I love being your English teacher.
我每周二都会制作新视频，我喜欢做你的英语老师。
That's it, and thanks so much for using Rachel's English.
就是这样，非常感谢你使用Rachel's English。